#### Contact

jagrn11@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jose-guerramsn-rn-cmsrn-crrn-4590a4103 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Healthcare Management

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Certified Rehabilitation Registered Nurse (CRRN)

**ENPC** 

Certified Medical/Surgical Registered Nurse

**ACLS** 

**BLS** 

# Jose Guerra, MSN RN CMSRN CRRN

**Chief Nursing Officer** 

Spring, Texas

# Summary

A committed and highly motivated situational, servant, visionary leader with 19 years of successful experience in healthcare (acute-care hospitals, long-term care, home healthcare, and outpatient clinics) management.

My philosophy of nursing: each individual across the lifespan deserves to receive a 5 star, safe, service which exceeds excellence. In order for this to be accomplished, the caregiver must be empathetic and altruistic in a holistic manner, those qualities with actions yield 'golden nursing care'......the 'nursing golden rule'.

# Experience

Encompass Health Rehabilitation Hospital The Vintage Chief Nursing Officer

November 2017 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Houston, Texas

(A for-profit 60 licensed bed acute rehab hospital)

Responsibilities: Oversight of clinical operations (Nursing, Respiratory, Dietary, Infection Control, Education). Direct reports include 6 clinical leaders, and 80 indirect reports.

#### Accomplishments:

- # Successful Triennial Joint Commission Survey
- # Disease-Specific Stroke Certification
- # Clinical outcomes exceeded benchmarks

ACT - Annual Average 8.57% - ranked #34

Falls - Annual Average 6.32 - ranked #18

- # Patient Scanning, HACs, and Patient Experience improved compared to previous year.
- # Decreased incremental OT, from 2.4% to 1.4% of worked hours.

- # Eliminated Contract Labor August 2018.
- # Increased CRRNs from 1 to 5 within 1 year.

Tomball Regional Medical Ctr
Director of Nursing: Med/Surg. Services
January 2013 - November 2017 (4 years 11 months)

(A for-profit 350 licensed bed acute care hospital)

Responsibilities: Oversight of 5 departments (Med/Surg., Pediatrics, Joint Destination Center, Telemetry / Neuro., and Clinical Decision Unit) which complement of 100 beds. Direct reports included Two Nurse Managers, Clinical Coordinator, and 190 FTE's.

#### Accomplishments:

- # Implementation of Destination Joint Center (Marshall Steele)
- # Development of innovative service line: ERAS program
- # Improved 8 categories of HCHAPs to > 75th percentile (Booster Campaign)
- # Decreased core measure fall outs to zero
- # Decreased over time from 10.97% to 2.35%
- # Decreased patient fall rate by 50%
- # Decreased Left without Treatment from ED by 60%
- # Increased employee satisfaction by 20%
- # Reduced nursing turnover rate from 41% to 11.3%
- # Developed Med/Surg. and Pediatric Handbook for New Graduate Nurses
- # Successful TJC survey with zero deficiencies in Med/Surg.
- # Decreased HAC's to below benchmarks.

#### NCISD

Health Services Director January 2011 - January 2013 (2 years 1 month)

Crdentia Nurse Leader 2008 - 2011 (3 years) Houston, Texas Area

Mountainview Healthcare Unit Supervisor 2006 - 2008 (2 years)

# Pine Shadow Retreat Nursing Home Unit Supervisor January 2002 - January 2006 (4 years 1 month)

Kidney Associates Team Lead 2001 - 2002 (1 year)

# Education

### **Excelsior College**

MSN , Nursing Administration · (2015 - 2017)

## **Excelsior College**

Bachelor's of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2011 - 2013)

# **Excelsior College**

Associate of Applied Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2009 - 2011)

# Anamarc College-Santa Teresa

Vocational Nursing, Licensed Practical/Vocational Nurse Training  $\cdot$  (2007 - 2008)

## Angelina College

Certified Medication Aide (2002 - 2002)